Guide to the Records of the 1948 Election Voting Study in Elmira, New York 1939-1972 (bulk 1948-1954) MS 196
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Questionnaires, 1948-1950; 8 Linear feet
  The series contains the completed questionnaires used in the Elmira study (although it is not known if every single completed questionnaire remains in the collection). Four "waves" of questionnaires, following the so-called "panel method" of repeated interviews, are found in the series. Three of these waves date from before the 1948 election (June, August and October) and a fourth from just after the election in November. Two waves of questionnaires from 1950 (April and July) are also in the series, although the relation of these to the study is unclear as they are not mentioned in the published results.
  The questionnaires, especially the three pre-election surveys, touched on an extensive array of matters, including the interviewee's attitude toward the various candidates in the primary and general campaigns, their intentions to vote one way or the other, the influences on their choices, and their views on key issues (notably Russia, labor and management relations, the growth of corporations and government regulation of industry, the Israeli-Arab conflict, and the United Nations). The questionnaires also include demographic information, including organizations that the interviewee associated with and the resulting political influences. In addition to the checked-off answers and brief notations on the questionnaires, there are also some longer form answers to interview questions. (Reproductions of the questionnaire forms can be found in an appendix in Bernard Berelson, et al.'s Voting.)
  In order to link the questionnaires to particular respondents and to each other, each questionnaire was given a unique code that was formed by reference to the wave, segment, and household interviewed. For example, the questionnaire numbered as 001-145-004 indicates that it was the first wave questionnaire, implemented in the 145th segment of Elmira, given to the fourth household/interviewee from that segment. Questionnaire 002-145-004 would be the second wave given to the same household. (A map showing the segment numbers and location can be found in Series I, in the folders "Maps of Elmira.")
  - Questionnaires (2 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 37-38)
    Includes questionnaires that appear to be outside the principal ones used in the survey. These are from Elmira and other locales, and might be test surveys.
  - Questionnaires. Segments 000-040 (10 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1-10)
  - Questionnaires. Segments 041-079 (14 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1-14)
  - Questionnaires. Segments 081-118 (13 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1-13)
  - Questionnaires. Segments 119-159 (14 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1-14)
  - Questionnaires. Segments 160-222 (14 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1-10)
  - Questionnaires. Segments 223-257 (12 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1-12)
  - Questionnaires. Segments 258-271 (7 folders), 1948 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1-7)
  - Blank Questionnaires, 1948 October (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1950 Opinion Survey. Segments 1-118 (4 folders), 1950 April (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9-12)
  - 1950 Opinion Survey. Segments 120-271 (4 folders), 1950 April (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - 1950 Final Questionnaire. Segments 1-271 (5 folders), 1950 July (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5-9)
  - 1950 Final Questionnaire. Late Returned Questionnaires, and Letters., 1950 August-December (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
- Series III. Reference Materials, 1947-1948; 1.88 Linear feet in one record carton, one document box, and 67 phonograph records
  The Reference Materials series includes mass media available in Elmira during the 1948 election campaign that may have had an influence on the voters. These included both print media and radio broadcasts from local station WENY, as recorded on phonograph records. The print media included local newspapers, corporate newsletters, and periodicals aimed at labor and other interest groups. The recordings are primarily of Fulton Lewis, Jr., the nationally-syndicated conservative broadcaster.
  The series is organized in two subseries:
  Subseries III.A. Print Matter
  Subseries III.B. Phonograph Records
  - Subseries III.A. Print Matter, 1947 December-1948 December; 1.21 Linear feet
    All the newspapers and periodicals are arranged by title
    The subseries includes newspapers and other periodicals that circulated in at least some quarters in Elmira during the 1948 election campaign. These included newspapers aimed at the general public, such as the weekly Chemung Valley Reporter, and periodicals intended for particular audiences, especially those with labor, corporate, and religious affiliations. The container list below includes the specific titles.
    - Chemung Valley Reporter (2 folders), 1948 May-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - CIO News, 1948 July-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - Chemung County Farm & Home Bureau & 4H Club News, 1948 June-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    - Democratic Digest, The Electronic Workers' Journal, Ford Facts, Elmira Labor Reviews, 1948 January-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    - Independent Women, International Fire Fighter, International Teamster, The Journeyman Barber, 1948 May-October (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
    - Labor, The Laborer, 1948 June-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
    - The Machinist, Machinist Monthly Journal, 1948 June-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    - The Modern Woodman, Moore News, Office Reporter, Office Worker, NYS Federation of Labor, 1947 December-1948 October (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
    - Railway Carmen's Journal, The Railway Conductor, 1948 May-December (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
    - The Typographical Journal, 1948 August-December (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
    - Union News Service, The Union Postal Clerk, United Automobile Workers, 1948 June-November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
    - The Catholic Courier,The Carpenter, 1948 September-December (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Magazine, 1948 May-December (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bendix Council News, Bendix Eclipse News, Blazes, The Bridge News Magazine, 1948 May-December (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    - American Federationist, American Flint, 1948 July-November (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
  - Subseries III.B. Phonograph Records, 1948 June-November; 0.67 Linear feet
    The subseries includes 67 recordings of radio broadcasts from Elmira station WENY. The bulk includes 50 records of Fulton Lewis, Jr.'s show (or his substitute during the summer of 1948, Kenneth G. Crawford). There are also 16 recordings of "Meet the Press" and one record with two spots, sponsored by the Progressive Party and by the Republican Party. Many of the record labels are stamped as "used," perhaps suggesting those were used in the election study.
    The subseries is arranged by radio program.
    Access Restrictions
    The phonograph records are restricted because of their fragility and because N-YHS has no equipment on which to play them.
    - Fulton Lewis, Jr. / Kenneth G. Crawford (50 records), 1948 June 14-November 3 (Disk 1-50)
      Crawford substituted for Lewis from July 19 through August 13.
    - "Meet the Press" (16 records), 1948 June 25-October 15 (Disk 51-66)
    - "Henry A. Wallace" (Progressive Party Sponsor) / "Political Talk" (Republican Party Sponsor), 1948 October (Disk 67)